Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 12 and District 12 Locals, 1937-1985 UE.4.1.12
ULS Archives & Special Collections
UE National Office Records Relating to District 12 and District 12 Locals
1937-1985
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America
UE.4.1.12
1.2 Linear Feet (1 box)
This series contains files on United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) District 12 and its locals collected by the UE national office. Included are correspondence, officer lists and charter applications.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
District 12 of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) was comprised of locals in the southeastern United States, including those in South Carolina, North Carolina, Florida, and Alabama. These locals that are still in existence are now part of the UE's Eastern Region. This series contains files on UE District 12 and its locals collected by the UE national office. Included are correspondence, officer lists and charter applications. Most of the correspondence is between UE national officers and district or local officers.
Previous Citation
UE National Office Records Relating to District 12 and District 12 Locals, 1937-1985, UE.4.1.12, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
This series has been arranged into two subseries. The first contains records pertaining to District 12. The other subseries contains records pertaining to specific locals within the district, and are further arranged numerically by local number into sections.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America in 1975, 1986, 1997, and 2001.
Related Material
UE Local 1201 Records, 1960s-1980s, UE.16.1202, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Records concerning the UE's Southern Organizing Campaign can be found in: UE Organizing Campaign Records, 1942-1990s, UE.7.1, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- Alabama -- History; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- Florida -- History; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- North Carolina -- History; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- South Carolina -- History; Labor; Clippings (Information artifacts); Minutes (Administrative records); Publications; Correspondence; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- Southeastern States -- History; Southeastern States; Alabama; Florida; Labor unions -- South Carolina -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions -- North Carolina -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions -- Florida -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions -- Alabama -- History -- 20th century; South Carolina; North Carolina; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America; Matles, James J.; Emspak, Julius; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. District 12
- District 12, 1.
  - District 12 Auto Mechanics Organization, January 23 - February 7, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Karl Bayer to James Carey, January 23, 1939; 1.
    - Carey to Bayer, February 7, 1939; 2.
  - District 12 Birmingham Western Electric Organization, December 1 - 13, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - W. F. McKenzie to Congress of Industrial Organizations, December 1, 1940; 1.
    - Allan Haywood to James Carey, December 5, 1940; 2.
    - Carey to McKenzie, December 13, 1940; 3.
  - District 12 Correspondence, November 22, 1939 - September 29, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - James Matles to E. B. Epping Regarding Federal Local Transfer and Fort Smith CIO, November 22, 1939; 1.
    - Maurice J. Dineen to James Carey Regarding El Paso Organization, August 21, 1939; 2.
    - Allan Haywood to Carey Regarding Fort Smith Federal Local Transfers with Haywood Letter to Toney Honey, July 30, 1940; 3.
    - James Matles to Emmett Ramsay Regarding Staff Members, September 29, 1953; 4.
  - District 12 Organization and Finances, 1972 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - District 12 Atlanta, GA, Morse Electro Organizing, 1973 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - District 12 Southern Organizing Campaign, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - District 12 Charlotte, NC, Westinghouse Warehouse, 1971 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - District 12 Wayne Yarborough, Tampa, FL, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - District 12 Tampa, FL, Organization Committee, 1970 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District 12 Charlotte, NC, Warehouse, 1982 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - District 12 Charlotte, NC, Signed Supplements, 1968 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District 12 Correspondence Regarding Southern Organizing, 1980 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - District 12 Temporary Organization and District Arrangements, 1983 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- District 12 Locals, 2.
  - Local 1201
    - Local 1201 Officers Lists, May 10, 1947 - September 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Local 1201 General Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Wadus Danton Regarding Dues and Veterans, June 18, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Local 1201 General Outgoing Correspondence, December 8, 1948 - March 29, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Myrtle Hall to Julius Emspak Regarding Blanks, December 8, 1948; 1.
      - George Markland to James Matles Regarding Staff Members, March 29, 1950; 2.
    - Local 1201 Tampa, FL, Westinghouse Electric Turbine Division Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Local 1201 Newspaper Clippings, April 1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - "Ammunition Plant Strike Begins", April 1953; 1.
      - "UE Local Here Hits Un-American Witness", undated; 2.
      - "Union to Demand Raises", undated; 3.
    - Local 1201 Organization, September 1 - October 1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Henry Fiering to James Matles, September 1, 1946; 1.
      - Fiering to Julius Emspak, September 17, 1946; 2.
      - Emspak to Fiering, October 1, 1946; 3.
    - Local 1201 Correspondence, November 27, 1947 - April 10, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Clara Fiering to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Negotiations, November 27, 1947; 1.
      - Rufus Paret to Arthur Kinoy, May 11, 1948; 2.
      - Secretary to James Matles to Henry Rhine, April 10, 1950; 3.
    - Local 1201 Strikes, Subsidies, and Other Monies, 1973 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Local 1201 Thank You Support Letter, Hugh Harley, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Local 1202
    - Local 1202 Ladson, SC, General Electric Steam Turbine Newsletters and Correspondence, 1975 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Local 1202 Organizing Campaign List, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Local 1204
    - Local 1204 Washington, NC, Atwood and Morrill Correspondence, 1979 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Local 1205
    - Local 1205 Tampa, FL, General Electric Newsletter and Correspondence, 1979 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Local 1238
    - Local 1238 Charter Application, November 29, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Local 1239
    - Local 1239 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to P. Tidewell Regarding Organization, April 7, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Local 1239 Outgoing Correspondence, F. Bidinbaugh Regarding Organization, March 31, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Local 1239 Per Capita Reports, March - June 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Local 1239 Notices of Delinquency, February - September 1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Local 1239 Organization, December 4, 1937 - January 29, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - CIO Charter Application, December 4, 1937; 1.
      - CIO Representative Report, December 10, 1937; 2.
      - Yelverton Cowherd to Julius Emspak, January 29, 1938; 3.
  - Local 1240
    - Local 1240 General Incoming Correspondence, July 1, 1938 - March 3, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - James Carey to Martin Eversole Regarding Labor Legislation, October 6, 1938; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to Georgia Bale Regarding Constitution, July 1, 1938; 2.
      - Emspak to Eversole Regarding Unemployment, December 13, 1938; 3.
      - Emspak to Eversole Regarding Organization, February 2, 1939; 4.
      - Emspak to Genevieve Roberson Regarding Walsh Healy, March 3, 1939; 5.
      - James Matles to Roberson Regarding Contracts, December 28, 1938; 6.
    - Local 1240 General Outgoing Correspondence, October 3, 1938 - January 1939 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Martin Eversole to James Carey Regarding Fair Labor Standards Act Wages, October 3, 1938; 1.
      - Eversole to Julius Emspak Regarding Organization and Negotiations, January 1939; 2.
    - Local 1240 Per Capita Reports, May - July 1938 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Local 1240 Notices of Delinquency, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Local 1240 Organization Attempt, March 26 - November 1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Charter Application, March 26, 1938; 1.
      - Harry Howard to Julius Emspak, March 26, 1938; 2.
      - Howard to Emspak, April 6, 1938; 3.
      - Notice of Issued Charter, April 7, 1938; 4.
      - William Mitchell to Howard, April 13, 1938; 5.
      - Howard to Mitchell, May 6, 1938; 6.
      - Howard to James Matles, June 15, 1938; 7.
      - Arbitration Award, November 1938; 8.
  - Local 1501
    - Local 1501 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to J. B. Nalley, April 25, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Local 1501 Per Capita Reports, July - September 1937 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Local 1501 Notices of Delinquency, November 1937 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Local 1501 Charter Application with Petition, June 19, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Local 1501 Birmingham, AL, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Local 1502
    - Local 1502 Charter Application, June 24, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Local 1503
    - Local 1503 Charter Application, July 14, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Local 1504
    - Local 1504 Charter Application, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Local 1508
    - Local 1508 Bluefield, WV, West Virginia Armature Company, 1937 - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Local 1509
    - Local 1509 Charter Application, September 18, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Local 1510
    - Local 1510 Charter Application, September 25, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Local 1510 Charlotte, NC, Southern Electric Equipment Company, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 49)